Cheng Wei

Curriculum Vitae

Contact Department of Computer Science

School of Computing AS6 05-22 Multimedia System Lab

Singapore, 117543

Phone: +6581289359

chengwe2@comp.nus.edu.sg

http://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~chengwe2/

Research Interests

Currently I am working on System support for multimedia applications, especially in streaming 3D models over network and distributed virtual environment. My other research interests include Computer Graphics, Distributed System, Peer-to-Peer System, and Concurrent Programming.

Education

Ph.D., Computer Science, Est. Dec 2009

National University of Singapore

Singapore

M.Eng, Communication Science and Engineering, 2005

Fudan University Shanghai, China

B.Eng, Civil Engineering, 1996

Tongji University Shanghai, China

Honors

Dean's Graduate Research Excellence Award

School of Computing, NUS, 2009

Best Paper Award, ACM Multimedia 2008

ACM Multimedia 2008

Employment

8/2008–11/2008 Part Time Teaching Assistant

8/2007–11/2007 Part Time Teaching Assistant

National of University of Singapore

Singapore

6/2005-7/2005 Intern

Alcatel Shanghai Bell Inc.

Shanghai, China

7/1996–9/2001 Civil Engineer

East China Civil Aviation Airport Design Institute

Shanghai, China

Publications

Journal Papers

Sebastien Mondet, Wei Cheng, Geraldine Morin, Romulus Grigoras, Frederic Boudon, and Wei Tsang Ooi. Compact and progressive plant models for streaming in networked virtual environments. *ACM Transactions on Multimedia Computing, Communications, and Applications(TOMCCAP)*, 5(3):21:1–22, 2009.

Hang Yu, Ee-Chien Chang, Wei Tsang Ooi, Mun Choon Chan, and Wei Cheng. Integrated optimization of video server resource and streaming quality over best-effort network. *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (IEEE TCSVT)*, 19(3):374–385, 2009.

Conference Papers

Wei Cheng, Dan Liu, and Wei Tsang Ooi. Peer-assisted view-dependent progressive mesh streaming. In *Proceedings of ACM MULTIMEDIA '09*, Beijing, China, October 2009.

Ransi De Silva, Wei Cheng, Dan Liu, Wei Tsang Ooi, and Shengdong Zhao. Towards characterizing user interaction with progressively transmitted 3D meshes (short paper). In *Proceedings of ACM MULTIMEDIA '09*, Beijing, China, October 2009.

Sebastien Mondet, Wei Cheng, Geraldine Morin, Romulus Grigoras, Frederic Boudon, and Wei Tsang Ooi. Streaming of plants in distributed virtual environments. In *Proceeding of ACM MULTIME-DIA'08*, Vancouver, BC, Canada, Octorber 2008.

Wei Cheng. Streaming of 3D progressive meshes. In *Proceedings of ACM MULTIMEDIA '08 (Doctoral Symposium Abstract)*, Vancouver, BC, Canada, October 2008.

Wei Cheng and Wei Tsang Ooi. Receiver-driven view-dependent streaming of progressive mesh. In *Proceedings of NOSSDAV'08*, Brauschweig, Germany, May 2008.

Wei Cheng, Wei Tsang Ooi, Sebastien Mondet, Romulus Grigoras, and Géraldine Morin. An analytical model for progressive mesh streaming. In *Proceedings of ACM MULTIMEDIA '07*, pages 737–746, Augsberg, Germany, September 2007.

Memberships and Activities

2008-present ACM Student Member

2008-present IEEE Graduate Student Member

6/2009-8/2009 Visiting Student to Singapore-MIT Gabmit Lab, MIT, Boston, USA

Technical Skills

Languages (most familiar to least familiar)

C, Python, C++, Lua, Erlang, Java, D, OCaml, Clojure, Haskell

Area

Linux Programming, OpenGL programming, Concurrent programming

Miscellaneous

Citizenship: China

Marital Status: Married

September 6, 2009